<resources>
    <string name="app_name">NSTU Diary</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_second">SecondActivity</string>

    <string name="title_activity_home">HomeActivity</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="about"><font color='#0D47A1'>About</font></string>
    <string name="title_activity_webview">WebviewActivity</string>
    <string name="preferences"><font color='#0D47A1'>Preferences</font></string>
    <string name="university_name"><![CDATA[NOAKHALI SCIENCE & TECHNOLOLGY UNIVERSITY]]></string>

    <string name="about_nstu">
        The creation of a band of skilled manpower equipped with latest knowledge of science and technology is a must to achieve a prestigious position in this modern world. As a part of ensuring quality education, with immense expectations of the southern coastal inhabitants of Bangladesh, a new university named Noakhali Science and Technology University (abbreviated as NSTU) was established on 15 July 2001 enacting the Noakhali Science and Technology University Act 2001. Finally, it started its academic activities on 22 June 2006. The inclusion of the study of humanities implies the urge felt by the concerned authority to create leaders who will fashion a more humane and just world. The university not only engages itself in teaching and research but also provides societal services for the benefit of rural and urban populations.
        \n\nAt present, it has six faculties (namely Faculty of Engineering &amp; Technology, Faculty of Science, Faculty of Social Science and Humanities, Faculty of Education Sciences, Faculty of Law and Faculty of Business Administration) and two institutes (namely Institute of Information Sciences and Institute of Information Technology). The faculties include twenty eight degree offering departments namely Department of Computer Science and Telecommunication Engineering (CSTE), Department of Fisheries &amp; Marine Science (FIMS), Department of Pharmacy, Department of Applied Chemistry and Chemical Engineering (ACCE), Department of Microbiology, Department of Applied Mathematics, Department of English,  Department of Environmental Science and Disaster Management (ESDM), Department of Food Technology and Nutrition Science (FTNS), Department of Business Administration, Department of Information and Communication Engineering (ICE), Department of Economics, Department of Biotechnology and Genetic Engineering  (BGE),  Department of Agriculture (AG), Department of Statistics, Department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering (EEE), Department of Bangladesh and Liberation War Studies, Department of Oceanography, Department of Biology and Molecular Biology, Department of Zoology, Department of Education, Department of Bangla, Department of Educational Administration, Department of Law, Department of Tourism and Hospitality Management, Department of Management information System, Department of Sociology, and Department of Social Welfare. The institutes include two degree offering departments namely Department of Information Science and Library Management and Department of Software Engineering.
        \n\nThe well furnished central library equipped with online library facilities has 13,511 printed books and 1500 printed journals apart from numerous e-books and e-journals. Since its establishment, NSTU has been running very smoothly. The teachers have extraordinary academic background and excellent skills of presentation. Presently, one fourth of the teachers are doing Ph.D. in different parts of the world. This is the only university in Bangladesh where three individual subjects based exclusively on information study namely Information Science, Information Technology, and Information and Communication Engineering is taught. International conferences, seminars and symposiums are frequently held with participation of the scholars from all over the world. Internal Programming contest is arranged regularly to sharpen the skill as a result of which many national and international awards in programming contests are already in the store of this university. Students of the department of Fisheries and Marine Science as well as the department of Oceanography with their extensive research on healthy marine resources privileged by the location of this university in a coastal arena are contributing greatly to the country’s blue economy.
        \n\nCo-curricular activities are extensively patronized. There are students’ organizations like NSTUMUNA, NSTU Debating Society, NSTU English Club, NSTU Business Club etc which work to develop leadership capacity of a student by promoting the art of public speaking, reasoning and logical thinking. Besides, NSTU Blood Donors Society, DreamBazz Filmz, Moshal, Protiddhoni, NSTU Photographic Society etc are there whose activities aim at the formation of a non-communal and progressive cultural mind. The way the national and international days are observed and different cultural festivals are celebrated with active participation of not only the students but also the local dwellers as well has turned the campus into a cultural capital of this southern region. The slogan “Green NSTU, Clean NSTU” has been an inspiring tonic among all in keeping this naturally blessed green campus neat and clean. The calm, quiet &amp; soothing environment of the campus, modeled upon the western modern universities like the University of Cambridge, is a wonderful escape for the researchers from the hustle and bustle of town life for an uninterrupted concentration on their study and research. Now-a-days, NSTU is lovingly addressed as ‘The Cambridge of the Coastal Terrain’. Each member of NSTU family is trying hard to make this addressing a reality.
    </string>

    <string name="msg_from_vc">
        It\'s a great pleasure to me to welcome you to Noakhali Science and Technology University(NSTU).This is the 27th public university which was established on 15th July 2001, and the academic activities start on 22th June 2006, having 13 teachers, 180 students with four departments namely Department of Computer Science and Telecommunication Engineering (CSTE), Department of Pharmacy, Department of Applied Chemistry and Chemical Engineering (ACCE) and Department of Fisheries and Marine Science (FIMS). Now the University made its standard world class and addressed as the <b>“Cambridge of the Coastal terrain.”</b> The University provides high-quality education, in-depth research, equipping students with the insight to address both local and global challenges.
        \n\nPresently, NSTU accommodates 28 Departments under 6 Faculties, 2 Institutes, over 300 teachers, and more than 5000 students. All of the mentors and supportive staffs of NSTU are committed to prepare our students to hard work, acquire skills, technical knowledge and enhance the capabilities that will help them adequately to cope in rapidly changing global environment. In NSTU there are highly qualified and experienced faculties. Around 50 highly qualified teachers whose have Ph.D. or Post-Doctorial and experience of working at world-class universities and research centers. Currently, about 70 teachers are doing Ph.D. at the different world ranking University in UK, USA, Japan, Australia, Europe, South Korea, and many other countries. We will strengthen our faculty to provide higher education of international standards in relevant areas and facilitate training programs for all of the teachers and officers through IQAC (Institutional Quality Assurance Cell).
        \n\nNSTU’s academic standards are accepted in worldwide, enjoying MoU (Memorandum of Understanding) with many famous universities, institutions and scholarly bodies from all over the world especially Hiroshima University, University of Stirling, Anglia Ruskin University, Kynunpouk National University, Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman Maritime University, Bangladesh providing students/teachers the opportunity to transfer to relevant programs and higher education, joint research etc. Beside academic development, we have enriched infrastructure also.
        \n\nWe have already reached the landmark of being Lower-middle income country by the declared vision 2021 and 2041 by Honorable Prime minister “Deshrotno Sheikh Hasina.” For that purpose, we have taken various steps for the University’s infrastructural development like Japan and Europe. For the demand of quality education and research facilities, we have ensured the construction of five halls for the students, five-storied Haji Idris Auditorium cum Multiple Building and adequate transportation facilities for the students, teachers, and officers. Establishment of multiple ten storied towers is going on, among those 1. The largest academic and Lab building 2. Teacher-Officer Tower 3. Provost and Assistant Provost Tower 4. Staff tower is notable. Apart from these, Establishment of three storied Medical center, eye-catching Central Mosque, and worship for the Hindu, Buddhist, and Christian students are going on. For nourishing co-curricular activities, BNCC and Rover Scout has been established. Very soon Building for the BNCC and Rover Scout will be constructed.
        \n\nIt\'s great news that we are going to start a world-class institute Sheikh Hasina Marine Institute where the researcher will work on the blue economy, delta formation, space research, material science, artificial intelligence, and nanotechnology. As the Vice-Chancellor of NSTU, I hope that continuous efforts for the University researchers, faculty members, students, concern stakeholders can be benefitted. I anticipate that this website will help you to know more about the university.
    </string>

    <string name="vc">Vice Chancellor</string>
    <string name="about_nstu_title">About NSTU</string>
    <string name="message_from_vc_title">Message From VC</string>

</resources>
